At the nail level, the normal angulation, which is approximately
爪における正常な角度は、約
165 degrees.
165度です。
If there is an inversion, it can actually indicate a sign of pulmonary failure.
もし反転がある場合、それは実際には肺機能不全の兆候を示し得ます。
So, nails like these, which are often brittle, bitten.
そのような、しばしば脆く、噛み砕かれた爪は。
These are nervous people or children who are bored.
それは神経質な方々か、あるいは退屈している子供たちです。
You also have a nail where you see horizontal lines.
また、水平線が見られる爪もあります。
This is a...
これは…
difficulty with nutrient absorption.
栄養素の吸収における困難を示します。
Then you have vertical lines
そして、垂直線が見られる場合、
of absorption at the intestinal level.
それは腸における吸収の問題です。
You are not absorbing correctly.
適切に吸収できていません。
Then sometimes you have small dots,
そして、時々小さな点が見られることがあります。
like that, small dots.
このように、小さな点です。
So they can be linked to...
それらは〜に関連している可能性があります。
Because I hit myself, it makes a small dot.
ぶつけると小さな点ができるからです。
Each finger represents a specific organ.
各指は特定の臓器を表します。
And if it's these small dots,
そして、もしこれらの小さな点であるならば、
it's mineral deficiencies or losses.
それはミネラルの欠乏または損失です。
Mainly zinc, iron,
主に亜鉛、鉄、
and copper, but especially zinc and copper. Why? For example, if I have an infection
そして銅ですが、特に亜鉛と銅です。なぜかというと、例えば感染症がある場合、
of
の
an intestinal type or if I have a pulmonary type infection, I will use my minerals
腸型、あるいは肺型の感染症がある場合、私はミネラルを使います。
and where
そして、どこに
are my minerals found? Well, they are found up there in my bones and in
私のミネラルがあるかというと、それらは私の骨や
my nails, and I will go get my reserves and I will use them to
私の爪にあります。そして私は貯蔵されているものを取りに行き、それを使って
bring my white blood cells
白血球を運ぶために、
to the right place. Once you have eliminated the infection through your white blood cell system,
適切な場所に運びます。あなたの白血球システムによって感染症を排除したら、
well, the mineral leaves with it.
そのミネラルも一緒に排出されます。
Hence the importance, to have a good immune system, of having a good mineral system.
したがって、良い免疫システムを持つためには、良いミネラルシステムを持つことが重要です。
So, nails like these, where there is an inversion, indicate a fragile lung and heart.
そのような、反転がある爪は、脆弱な肺と心臓を示します。
Sometimes, on the nails, you really have a very significant stop like that.
爪に、非常に顕著な成長停止線が見られることがあります。
Either it's a fungus, so an immune deficiency, or it's really a deep metabolic problem
それは真菌感染症、すなわち免疫不全であるか、あるいは本当に深刻な
that is expressing itself.
深い代謝性の問題が発現しているかのどちらかです。
Sometimes spoon-shaped nails can express an absorption or storage problem.
時折見られる匙状爪は、吸収または
to do with a too rapid degradation of red blood cells. If there is bulging, it is
貯蔵の問題を示唆している可能性があります。
cardiac
赤血球の過剰な分解と関連しています。もしバチ状指が見られる場合、それは
or Vasquez's disease. The absence of a lunula expresses a lack of vitality. It's the
心臓性の問題です。
little
あるいはヴァスケス病です。爪半月の欠如は活力の欠如を表します。それは
white part here. I take someone's nail and you will
小さな
press on your nail. I press,
ここにある白い部分です。誰かの爪を取り、あなたは
it whitens and then it comes back. No problem with the blood, no problem with anemia.
自分の爪を押してください。私が押すと、
However, not enough lunula. A yellow nail is a sign of a fresh liver.
白くなり、すぐに色が戻ります。血液に問題はなく、貧血の問題もありません。
while a blue nail is a sign of a fragile heart or lung symptom.
しかし、爪半月が不十分です。黄色い爪は肝臓の問題の兆候です。
If the lunula is bluish, be careful, it can indicate a disturbed liver.
一方、青い爪は、脆弱な心臓または肺の症状の兆候です。
If the lunula is red, it is an early sign of a possible heart problem,
爪半月が青みがかった色をしている場合、注意が必要です。それは肝機能障害を示唆する可能性があります。
especially if the tip of the tongue is very red.
爪半月が赤い場合、それはおそらく心臓の問題の早期の兆候です。
Hands or bodies that are clammy, you take them in your hand,
特に舌先が非常に赤い場合はそうです。
they are cold and clammy. What is it?
手や体が湿っている人、彼らの手を取ると、
It indicates a thyroid imbalance, or
冷たく湿っています。これは何でしょうか？
If it's someone who is, for example, thin with very bulging eyes
それは甲状腺機能の不均衡、あるいは
and clammy hands, it's a thyroid imbalance.
例えば、眼球突出があり痩せている人の場合、
Always check the adrenals, don't forget.
そして手が非常に湿っている場合、それは甲状腺機能の不均衡です。
Maybe his adrenals are empty and he can't convert his T3 to T4.
常に副腎を診ることを忘れないでください。
Remember to think about the thyroid-adrenal tandem or a hepatic problem of
おそらく彼の副腎は疲弊しており、T3をT4に変換することができないのかもしれません。
congestive type.
甲状腺と副腎の連携、あるいは肝臓の
People who are sensitive to cold, the exhaustion of ancestral kidney energy
鬱血性の問題です。
or...
冷え性のある人々は、腎の先天の気の枯渇、
also a thyroid problem, hypothyroidism.
あるいは...
The hair.
甲状腺の問題、すなわち甲状腺機能低下症も考えられます。
Gray hair in a very young person can indicate an imbalance in the absorption
髪。
of certain amino acids.
若年者の白髪は、吸収の不均衡を示唆する可能性があります。
So check what's happening in the intestines and liver.
特定のアミノ酸におけるものです。
But what's interesting is to observe in some people the discoloration
したがって、腸および肝臓の状態を評価してください。
of the eyebrows.
しかし興味深いのは、特定の人々において脱色が観察されることです。
It's a sign of food or other allergies.
眉毛の部位に。